公元7.953年夏天，有消息说，一颗外国制造的原子弹在美国境外的某个地方爆炸了。
In the summer of 7.953, it was announced that an atomic bomb of foreign on'g/'n had been exploded somewhere outside of the United States.
不久以后，有人指出，根据科学的报告，这种原子反应起源于非太平洋水域的一个偏远地区，
Shortly thereafter, it was indicated that this atomic reaction, according to scientific repon's, had originated in a remote area in non'h pacific waters,
位于日本群岛北部和北极圈之间的某个地方。
somewhere between the northern tio of the Japanese islands and the arctic circle.
下面是关于那次爆炸的报道。
This is the story of that explosion.
哦!
Oh!
蒙特尔教授。我是先驱论坛报的麦卡利。
Professor montel. I'm mccleary of the herald tribune.
哦,是的。你好!
Oh, yes. How do you do?
我知道你要去维也纳向中欧高级科学家联盟发表演讲。
I understand that you're going to Vienna to address the, uh, central European federation of advanced scientists.
这是正确的。
That is correct.
我会读一篇关于中子发射和原子核碰撞的论文。
I will read a paper on the emission of neutrons and collision of nuclei.
谢谢您,教授。
Thank you, professor.
美国原子能委员会的成员会出席吗?
Will any of the American atomic energy commission be present?
我对此表示怀疑。
I doubt it.
失陪一下，先生们?
Will you excuse me, gentlemen?
是的。
Oui.
教授。原谅我。
Professor. Excuse me.
有一两点我想澄清一下。
There's one or two points I'd like to get clarified.
恕我失陪，先生们。飞机正在等待。
You will have to excuse me, gentlemen. The plane is waiting.
这个女孩是谁?
Who's the girl?
这里是BBC最新新闻。
This is the BBC with the latest news bulletin.
ll/lontel教授，著名的核物理学家和原子科学家，在去维也纳参加一个会议的途中失踪。
Professor ll/lontel, famous nuclear physicist and atomic scientist, has vanished while en route to attend a conference in Vienna.
对警方来说，朗泰尔教授的失踪完全是个谜。。
Professor ll/lontel's disappearance is a complete mystery to the police.
今天有权威人士透露这位前诺贝尔奖得主就是著名科学家认为消失在铁村后面的污秽物。
Authoritative sources re veal today that the former nobel prize winner is the filth noted scientist believed to have vanished behind the iron cun'ain.
ll/lontel教授最后一次出现是在维也纳的国际机场。
Professor ll/lontel was last seen at the international airpon' in Vienna.
关于ll/lontel教授下落的猜测还在继续。
Speculation as to the whereabouts of professor ll/lontel continues.
这位著名的科学家失踪已经10天了，到目前为止，警方仍无法提供任何解释。
Ten days have elapsed since the distinguished scientist vanished, and so far police have been unable to offer any explanation.
当局现在确信ll/lontel教授不是被绑架的他的失踪是有预谋的。
Authorities are now convinced that professor ll/lontel was not kidnapped and that his disappearance was pan' of a prearranged plan.
维也纳机场的官员透露，这位科学家持有外交护照。
Airpon' officials in Vienna re veal that the scientist carried a diplomatic passpon'.
搜寻ll/lontel教授的工作持续到第四周。
The search for professor ll/lontel continues into the fourth week.
有趣的是，尽管这个故事在美国和其他自由世界的报纸上占据了头版位置，
It is interesting to note that while the story has been given front-page space in newspapers in the United States and all other parts of the free world,
苏联官方喉舌《真理报》到目前为止还没有注意到这一点。
pravda, the official mouthpiece of the Soviet union, has, as yet, failed to take note on it.
-李·斯托克威尔下士?——正确的。
- Corporal Lee stockwell? - Right.
- R.J.麦克杜格尔先生?——这是正确的。
- Mr. R.J. Macdougall? - That's right.
-富兰克林·梅瑞狄斯先生——这是正确的。
- Mr. Franklin Meredith. - That's correct.
琼斯!
Jones!
恐怕你弄错了。我的名字叫macdougall。
I'm afraid you're mistaken. My name's macdougall.
你和我以前在潜艇服役时认识的一个军官长得一模一样。
You're a dead ringer for an officer I used to know in the submarine service.
对不起。
Sorry.
Macdougall先生吗?
Mr. Macdougall?
是的。
Yeah.
我的名字叫艾迪。
My name is eddy.
你的指令。
Your instructions.
有辆出租车在等你。司机知道地址。
There is a taxi waiting for you. The driver knows the address.
出租车63号。
Taxi number 63.
63号。
Number 63.
好吧。
Okay.
这是它。
This is it.
-你最好等我。-不，我现在就走。
- You better wait for me. - No, I go now.
等一下。如果我还需要你呢?我在哪里可以找到你?
Wait a minute. What if I need you again? Where can I find you?
-你叫什么名字?——艾迪。
- What's your name? - Eddy.
Macdougall先生吗?
Mr. Macdougall?
-是的。请进，跟我来。
- Yeah. - Come in, please, and follow me.
请小心脚下。
Watch your step, please.
-别告诉我你也叫艾迪。-“艾迪”是密码。
- Now don't tell me your name is eddy too. - “Eddy” is the password.
我是藤森研田，琼斯指挥官。
I'm hokada fujimori, commander Jones.
我很高兴见到你。
I'm very pleased to meet you.
谢谢。刚才我还以为这是密室外的东西呢。
Thanks. For a minute there, I thought this was something out of inner sanctum.
啊，你瘦了一点。
Ah, you've lost a little weight.
我在节食。
I'm on a diet.
我打赌泰勒队长长胖了?
I'll bet captain Taylor put a little fat on, huh?
-他在哪里?-我很遗憾地告诉你，你的朋友死了。
- Where is he? - I'm sorry to tell you, your friend is dead.
死了吗?
Dead?
他的飞机在北极探险返回途中坠毁。
His plane crashed returning from an arctic expedition.
没有人幸存下来。
No one survived.
他从来就不喜欢飞行。
He never did like to fly.
他为什么要我来这里?那5000美元是做什么用的?
Why did he want me to come here? What was the 5,000 for?
这是预付的酬劳泰勒队长很确定你会帮我们完成任务。
It's an advance payment for a job captain Taylor was certain you would do for us.
——推进?——是的。
- Advance? - Yes.
-我什么时候开始?——没有问题吗?
- When do I start? - Without questions?
为什么说话?如果泰勒让我去做那份工作，那肯定很合适。
Why talk? If Taylor lined me up for the job, it must be kosher.
有些人可能不认为这是洁食。
Some people might not exactly call it kosher.
请在这里。
In here, please.
先生们,指挥官琼斯。
Gentlemen, commander Jones.
——Mcauliff先生。-你好，先生。
- Mr. Mcauliff. - How do you do, sir?
-舒曼上校。-你好吗?
- Colonel schuman. - How are you?
——Aylesworth先生。-你好!
- Mr. Aylesworth. - How do you do?
和蒙特尔教授。
And professor montel.
-那个科学家蒙特尔?——是的。
- Montel, the scientist? - Yes.
所有人都在追杀你，教授。
Everybody and his brother is gunning for you, professor.
他们说你跳到了铁幕后面。
They say you skipped behind the iron curtain.
如你所见，只有一扇木门。
As you can see, only a wooden door.
-很高兴你来了。-谢谢你，先生。
- Glad you're here. - Thank you, sir.
你这里的布局真不错。
Well, it's quite a layout you got here.
你们是做什么生意的?
What kind of business are you gentlemen in?
调查的业务。
The business of investigation.
这些无人居住的北太平洋岛屿位于自由世界和铁幕之间的中立水域。
The scientific investigation of these uninhabited north pacific islands that lie in neutral waters between the free world and the iron curtain.
啊哈。
Uh-huh.
我们的推论使我们相信其中一个岛屿…我们不知道是哪一个，琼斯先生…已经准备好作为原子武器的军火库。
Our deductions make us believe that one of these islands... We don't know which one, Mr. Jones... Has been prepared as an arsenal for atomic weapons.
你的朋友泰勒上尉自愿接受摄影任务来找出答案。
Your friend captain Taylor volunteered to undertake a photographic mission to find out.
——自愿?——是的。
- Volunteered? - Yes.
——免费吗?——免费。
- For free? - For free.
他是那时出的车祸吗?
Is that when he had the accident?
这不是偶然。他的飞机被击落了。
It was no accident. His plane was shot down.
我们刚刚打印的这张照片来自他失事飞机上的照相机。
This photograph we have just printed came from the camera of his salvaged plane.
在海军服役三十年，却因为一张照片而被杀。
Thirty years in the Navy, and he gets killed for a picture.
免费的。
For free.
每个人都有自己活着的理由，琼斯先生，也都有自己的死的代价。
Each man has his own reason for living, Mr. Jones, and his own price for dying.
这是泰勒船长的代价。
This was captain Taylor's price.
什么都没有，教授。这是一个惨败。
There's nothing there, professor. It's a washout.
我不太确定。扩展这些行。
I wouldn't be too certain. Extend these lines.
它们可能是原子拱顶建筑。
They could be atomic vault constructions.
这里也可能是混凝土跑道的一部分。
And over here could also be part of a concrete runway.
看。听着，在我们进一步讨论之前，我想知道你们到底代表哪个国家?
Look. Look, before we go any further, exactly what country do you men represent?
我们作为个人代表许多国家。
We represent many countries, as private individuals.
我们是科学家、前政治家、商人。
We are scientists, former statesmen, businessmen.
所有志愿者都独立行动，为了共同的事业，对抗共同的敌人。
All volunteers acting independently for a common cause against a common enemy.
作为个人，我们可以在不侵犯任何中立水域的前提下进行科学调查。
As private individuals, we can conduct this investigation on a scientific basis without violating any neutral waters.
如果我们的怀疑得到了证实，我们就可以将我们的发现公之于众。
And if what we suspect is verified, we can then make our findings public.
那又有什么用呢?
And what good will that do?
你不觉得真相值得知道吗?
Don't you think the truth is worth knowing?
难道你不相信事实证据能一劳永逸地确定侵略者的身份和意图吗?
Don't you believe that factual proof will establish, once and for all, both the identity and the intention of the aggressor?
谁知道呢?但我在这幅画中处于什么位置呢?
Who knows? But where do I fit into the picture?
我们要你指挥一艘船去这些岛屿视察。
We want you to command a ship for an inspection tour of these islands.
-什么样的船?——一艘潜水艇。
- What kind of a ship? - A submarine.
我们知道，在第二次世界大战期间，你曾四次指挥潜艇在这个地区进行侦察巡逻。
We know that four times during world war ii, you commanded a submarine reconnaissance patrol in this very area.
我记得，你在这片海域与我的国家作战时取得了巨大的成功。
As I recall, you were extremely successful in these waters when you fought my country.
这次的敌人不同了，琼斯先生，但水是一样的。
This time the enemy is different, Mr. Jones, but the waters are the same.
你已经收到了5000美元。
You received already $5,000.
两万美元会存入你的账户在你选择的任何银行你可以把蒙泰尔教授送到这个岛上。
20,000 in United States currency will be deposited to your account in any bank you elect to chauffeur professor montel to this island.
如果你能把他带着所有他想要的信息安全带回来，还能得到两万五。
And another 25,000 bonus when you bring him back safely with all the information he seeks.
那潜艇呢?它也是自愿的吗?
What about the sub? Did it volunteer too?
没人能在垃圾场找到一流的潜艇，琼斯先生。
One does not pick up a first-class submarine in the junkyard, Mr. Jones.
我们打捞了一艘日本潜艇。
We have salvaged a Japanese submarine.
——什么类?-我- 203。
- What class? - I-203.
污水管。有一个跟踪了我六个小时。泰勒，看看她?
Sewer pipe. Had one on my tail once for six hours. Taylor look her over?
——是的。-开始给她重新装修?
- Yes. - Start getting her refitted?
——是的。——武装?
- Yes. - Armed?
琼斯先生，这次任务的目的是科学调查，不是战斗。
Mr. Jones, the object of this mission is scientific investigation, not combat.
教授……我是指挥官吗?
Professor... Am I in command?
——这是正确的。-那我们就武装潜艇。
- That's right. - Then we arm the sub.
前提是你想让我把你毫发无损地救回来。
That is, if you want me to get you back in one piece.
你还救了一名船员吗?
Did you also salvage a crew?
我们挑选了有经验的志愿者。
We have picked volunteers, experienced men.
船上将有两名科学家。
There will be two scientists on board.
蒙泰尔教授和他的助手杰拉德教授。
Professor montel and his assistant, professor Gerard.
我们不确定是哪个岛，但有一艘货船，江清号，以前载着混凝土和重金属来过这片区域好几次。
We aren't positive which island it is, but a certain freighter, the kiang ching, has been up to this area several times before with cargos of concrete and heavy metals.
她又在天津装货了。
She's loading again at tientsin.
上次我跟踪一艘货船，我的工资是每月650美元，我还得自己买制服。
The last time I tailed a freighter, my price was 650 a month, and I had to buy my own uniforms.
好吧。我需要我自己的关键人物，那些曾经为我效力的人。
All right. I want my own key men, men who've served with me before.
你说出他们的名字，我们就能抓到他们。
You name them, and we'll get them.
你懂我吗?为现金。
Like you got me, huh? For cash.
如果它是必要的。
If it's necessary.
就像我之前说的，琼斯先生，每个人都有自己活着的理由和死的代价。
As I said before, Mr. Jones, each man has his own reason for living and his own price for dying.
我希望，对我们所有人来说，这将是一个一路顺风。
I hope, for all of us, that it will be a bon voyage.
乔凡内尔帮他拉线。
Giovanel help him with the line.
Giovanel你!你，卡皮诺，帮他弄鱼雷。
Giovanel you! You, carpino, give him a hand with the torpedo.
你觉得我有几只手，纽曼?
How many hands you think I got, neuman?
你叫纽曼先生。
Mr. Neuman to you.
记得把电池上的读数告诉我。
Now, make sure you give me the reading on that battery.
对了,队长。
Right, skipper.
来吧。来吧!
Come on. Come on!
来吧，伙计们。把它!来吧!
Bring it on, boys. Bring it around! Come on!
嘿，来吧。简单的现在。来吧。
Heyl come on now. Easy now. Come on.
来吧。来吧。好吧,。
Come on. Come on. All right, hold.
好吧,男孩。紧紧抓住防滑钉鞋。
All right, boys. Make it fast to the cleats.
嘿。
Hey.
-你从来不洗澡吗?-闭嘴。
- Don't you ever take a bath? - Ah, shut up.
“啊,闭嘴。你的词汇量就这么多吗?
“Ah, shut up.” is that the extent of your vocabulary?
你为什么要放弃摔跤呢?
What'd you ever give up the wrestling racket for anyway?
我刚发现那是假的。
I just found out it was phony.
这就是问题所在……我说，这就是这些假摔跤手的问题所在。
That's the trouble with these... I say, that's the trouble with these phony wrestlers, dugboat.
-他们从不洗澡。-我们也是。
- They never take a bath. - We do too.
嘿,joto。嘿,joto。后阀不转了。
Hey, joto. Hey, joto. The after valve won't turn.
——什么?-后阀不转。
- What? - The after valve won't turn.
不,不。另一种方法。
No, no. The other way.
都反过来了。难怪你们这些家伙会输掉战争，有这样的潜艇。
Everything backwards. No wonder you blokes lost the war, with subs like this.
——队长。-是的。
- Skipper. - Yeah.
-那个叫威尔斯的家伙…任何好吗?-澳大利亚最好的工程师。
- That guy welles... any good? - Best engineer out of Australia.
-要是有威尔伯就好了。-是的。
- Wish we had wilbur. - Yeah.
有了查理·威尔伯操纵船首帆上的引擎，就没什么可担心的了。
With Charlie wilbur handling the engines on the bowfin, there was nothing to worry about.
听说他现在是脱衣舞娘了。
Hear he's a three-striper now.
是的，我听说了。
Yeah, so I hear.
船长，二号瞄准器坏了。
Skipper, that number two scopes don't work.
-怎么了?-没办法把锈去掉。
- What's the matter with it? - Can't get the rust out of it.
-第一名怎么样?-我没检查。
- How 'bout number one? - Didn't check it.
把她抬起来，动态心电图。
Lift her up, holter.
上面的教授要见船长。
The professor topside wants to see the captain.
让他下来。
Send him down.
他是幕后黑手。
He's part of the brass behind this setup.
如果他看起来很眼熟，什么都别说。稍后我将解释。
Now, if he looks familiar, don't say anything. I'll explain later.
你好,教授。欢迎登机，长官-船长。
- Hello, professor. Welcome aboard, sir. - Captain.
好吧，我们试着用一点口水和大量的汗水把这个下水管道组装起来。
Well, we're trying to put this sewer pipe together with a little spit and a lot of sweat.
-我想我们会解决的。-琼斯上尉。
- I guess we'll make it all right. - Captain Jones.
有什么事吗?有什么问题吗?
What's the matter? Is there something wrong?
很抱歉，我们不能允许你的船员参加这次探险。
I'm sorry to say we cannot permit one of your crew to make this expedition.
你是什么意思?他们都是精心挑选的。
What do you mean? They were all handpicked.
-我们不能相信这个。——谁?
- We cannot trust this one. - Who?
鱼雷手，雷夫尼克。
The torpedo man, revnik.
你选的人之一。
Oh, one of the men you picked.
我本可以一直告诉你的。knothead。
I could have told you that all the time. A knothead.
你也检查了我所有的人吗?
Did you screen all my men too?
非常亲密，包括你。
Very closely, including you.
——好的。我马上把莱夫尼克处理掉。——好。
- Okay. I'll get rid of revnik right away. - Good.
霍尔特,我希望……
Holter, I want...
她是替补吗，医生?
She the replacement, doc?
先生们，这是杰勒德教授，我的助手，我的得力助手。
Gentlemen, this is professor Gerard, my assistant and my right arm.
-你好。-丹尼斯，这是琼斯队长。
- Hiya. - Denise, this is captain Jones.
-琼斯上尉。-很高兴认识你，教授。
- Captain Jones. - Glad to know you, professor.
如果我知道这件事，我就会降价了。
Well, if I'd known about this, I'd have cut my price.
伙计们，这两位教授要跟我们一起去。
Boys, these two professors are going with us as cargo.
——什么?-你听到了。
- What? - You heard me.
你的垫圈爆了吗?没人会把女人带上船。
Have you blown a gasket? Nobody takes a female along in a pigboat.
听着，小子，你要跟我说他们是坏运气吗?
Look, junior, you gonna give me that 2,000-year-Old Navy bilge that they're bad luck?
看看她。这有什么不好的?
Take a look at her. What's so bad about that?
一文不值。完全没有啊，他们都是约拿。它的传统。
Nothin'. Absolutely nothin'i ah, they're all Jonahs. It's traditional.
船长，我已经决定了。别把我算在内。
Look, skipper, I made up my mind. Count me out.
好吧。
Okay.
还有人吗?
Anybody else?
我给你们五分钟时间好好想想，记住，如果有必要，我可以把你们每个人都换掉。
I'll give you jokers five minutes to sleep on it, and remember, iflhaveto, I can replace every one of you.
队长，我也不喜欢这样。
Captain, I do not like it either.
哦,scusami。
Oh, scusami.
也许你是对的。
Perhaps you are right.
在你看来，我是一个…一个女性。
In your estimation, I am a... a female.
但首先我是个科学家，是个好科学家。
But first I am a scientist and a good one.
我不是唯一一个非你们性别的科学家。
And I am not the only scientist who is not of your sex.
有很多。
There are many.
比如Lise meitner博士，他在原子弹的研制中发挥了重要作用。
Like Dr. Lise meitner, who played an important part in the development of the atom bomb.
比如发现镭的居里夫人。
Like madame curie, who discovered radium.
我是在实验室里长大的。
I have grown up in laboratories.
我这辈子都在和男人打交道。
All my life, I have worked with men.
我从来没有干涉过他们，他们也从来没有怨恨过我。
Never have I interfered, and never have they resented me.
montel教授和我…有很多事情要完成。
Professor montel and I have... Have much to accomplish.
多。
Much.
如果你不让我的…我的出现是…一场小叛乱。
And I shall appreciate it if you would not let my... my presence be the cause of... of a minor mutiny.
我喜欢你。
I like you.
我喜欢你们所有人。
I like you all.
我会尽我最大的努力让你喜欢我……
And I shall try my best to make you like me...
作为一个科学家。
As a scientist.
天啊，这对一个女人来说太拗口了!
Man, that was quite a mouthful for a female!
这是没有女性。这是一个科学家!
That's no female. That's a scientist!
好吧。来吧。我们还有很多工作要做。我们走吧。
All right. Come on. We got a lot of work to do. Let's go.
嗨，藤森先生，教授。
Hi, Mr. Fujimori, professor.
-你的助理呢?-你准备好起航了吗?
- Where's your assistant? - Are you prepared to sail?
明天我们进行潜泳测试后我再通知你。
I'll let you know tomorrow after we make the running dive tests.
我们已经没有明天了。
There's no tomorrow left for us.
江青号货轮半小时前从天津启航了。
The freighter kiang ching sailed from tientsin a half hour ago.
-你必须马上离开。-你在说什么?
- You must leave right away. - What are you talking about?
我们才工作了两个星期。这个浴缸还有很多工作要做。
We only been working for two weeks. We've got a lot of work left to do on this tub.
你必须在天黑前离开，才能赶上她。-正在进行的测试呢?
- You must leave by dark to overtake her. - What about the running tests?
作为一个业余爱好者，我建议我们在跑步的时候试试跑步测试?
As an amateur, might I suggest that we try the running test while we are running?
博士，失去潜艇的方法有上百种。
Doc, there are about a hundred ways of losing a submarine.
你刚刚想出了最好的一个。
You've just come up with one of the best.
我们还没检查鱼雷发射管呢。
We haven't even checked the torpedo tubes yet.
你知道如果我们要叫鱼的话意味着什么吗?这意味着我们死了。
You know what that means if we have to call on fish? It means we're dead.
你今晚必须离开。
You've got to leave tonight.
好吧，老兄，这次旅行你买了。你想让我试试吗?
Okay, buster, you're buying this trip. You want me to chance it?
这不是我们想要的，琼斯上尉。这是必须要做的。
It's not what we want, captain Jones. It's what must be done.
好吧。只要这位教授知道他是为了什么才进来的。
All right. Just as long as the professor here knows what he's letting himself in for.
我们已经安排飞机联系，告诉你江清的位置。
We've arranged airplane contact to give you position on the kiang ching.
-他们怎么联系我们，用信号灯还是无线电?-两者都不是没有风险的。
- How'll they contact us, blinker or radio? - Neither is without risk.
我们认为掉软木塞最安全。
We've decided cork drop is safest.
这包含您的代码，这包含您的联系人日程安排。
This contains your code, and this contains your schedule for contacts.
哦，还有一件事。
Oh, just one more thing.
我需要一个明确的指示，详细说明我的具体权力。
I want a clear-cut directive detailing my specific authority.
都在这里，船长。
You'll find it all in here, captain.
在海上，完全由你指挥。
At sea, you are in complete command.
在陆地上，蒙泰尔教授负责指挥。
On land, professor montel is in command.
我能祝你好运吗?
May I wish you the best of luck?
谢谢。
Thanks.
现在正是时候，纽曼先生。
Well, now's as good a time as any, Mr. Neuman.
-把她带到潜望镜深度。——是的,先生。
- Take her down to periscope depth. - Yes, sir.
清晰的桥梁!
Clear the bridge!
潜水!
Dive!
站在那边。你会没事的。
Stand right over there. You'll be all right.
——谢谢。-杰勒德教授，把手给我。
- Thank you. - Professor Gerard, give me your hand.
注意顶端的横档。这是谋杀。
Watch that top rung. It's murder.
——谢谢。——欢迎你。
- Thank you. - You're welcome.
你坐在这里。
You sit right here.
船长，在潜望镜深度修整完毕。
Captain, trim satisfactory at periscope depth.
- - - - - -很好。Joto。——是的,先生?
- Very well. Joto. - Yes, sir?
帮威尔斯把右舷引擎的蓝图翻译一下，好吗?
Give welles a hand with those starboard engine blueprint translations, will you?
我会处理的，队长。
I'll take care of it, captain.
fonnard鱼雷室一切都很紧张。
Everything's tight in the fonnard torpedo room.
我们要把她弄到深处去。检查所有站点。让我知道。
We're gonna try her down deep. Have all stations checked. Let me know.
哦,是的,队长。
Ay, ay, captain.
这就是我们今天谈到的测试，教授。
This is that test we were talking about today, professor.
——现在?——现在。
- Now? - Now.
不要紧张。如果我们崩溃了，你就没机会感受了。
Don't get nervous. If we crack up, you won't get a chance to feel it.
不要着急。没事的。
Take it easy. It'll be all right.
把她放在下面，纽曼先生。
Put her on the bottom, Mr. Neuman.
下降2度。
Two degrees down bubble.
——洪水负面。——洪水负面。
- Flood negative. - Flood negative.
哦，谢谢，李成。
Oh, thanks, chin Lee.
咖啡,教授?——不,谢谢。
- Coffee, professor? - No, thanks.
-你呢?-不用了，谢谢。
- How 'bout you? - No, thank you.
两百英尺，卡比塔先生。
Two hundred feet, kapita'n.
最好等一下，教授。
Better hold on, professor.
好吧。现在我们来看看能不能冲上屋顶。
All right. Now let's see if we can hit the roof.
-把她抬上去，纽曼先生。-关闭所有主压载通风口。
- Take her up, Mr. Neuman. - Close all main ballast vents.
-准备浮出水面。-准备浮出水面。
- Stand by to surface. - Stand by to surface.
——表面。——表面。
- Surface. - Surface.
-炸掉所有主镇流器!-吹灭所有主镇流器。
- Blow all main ballasts! - Blow all main ballasts.
空气库是怎么回事，动态心电图?
What's with the air banks, holter?
空气库已经干了。
The air bank's dry.
打开应急银行让他们听电话。
Open the emergency banks. Put 'em on the line.
他们打不开。
They won't open.
它们必须打开。我们已经检查了一切。
They've got to open. We've checked everything.
这些标志都搞混了。我要试每一个瓣膜。
These signs are all fouled up. I'll have to try every valve.
不，等一下。
No, wait a minute.
乔托，到控制室来。解开这些日本符号。
Joto, come to the control room. Unsnarl these Japanese signs.
我可以翻译。上面写着"打开应急空气库"
I can translate it. That one reads, “open emergency air bank.”
——什么?"打开应急空气库"
- What? - “Open emergency air bank.”
去做吧。试一试。
Go ahead. Try it.
-空中银行上线了。——好。谢谢。
- Air bank's on the line. - Good. Thanks.
好吧。把她放在屋顶上。
Okay. Put her on the roof.
——队长。-是的。没事吧，卡皮诺?
- Skipper. - Yeah. Everything all right, carpino?
只是填料腺体周围有几处漏水。我标记他们。
Just a few leaks around the stuffing glands. I marked them.
好吧。彻底搜查，斯基。
Okay. Make a full sweep, ski.
都清楚,队长。
All clear, skipper.
钻井平台为红色。范围。
Rig for red. Up scope.
你最好搬出去，教授。
You better move out, professor.
这有助于我们的眼睛适应黑暗时，我们上去。
This helps get our eyes used to the dark when we go up.
打开舱门，holter。
Open the hatch, holter.
你翻译得很好，医生。
You did a good job translating that sign, doc.
杰勒德教授是摩尔。
Professor Gerard is mol.
-摩尔?-精通东方语言。
- Mol? - Master of oriental languages.
哦?启封后。启封后。
Oh? Tres bon. Tres bon.
范围。
Down scope.
很高兴你能加入，教授。
Glad to have you aboard, professor.
很高兴能上船，船长。
Glad to be aboard, captain.
队长。教授想知道是否可以上来呼吸一下新鲜空气。
Captain. The professor wants to know if it's all right to come up for fresh air.
——哪一个?-有胡子的那个。
- Which one? - The one with the beard.
哦。好吧。
Oh. Okay.
航向355，双引擎全速前进。
Come to course 355, ahead full on both engines.
哦,是的,队长。
Ay, ay, captain.
你不需要带伞，教授。她是一条干船。
You won't need your umbrella, professor. She's a dry boat.
没什么好担心的。
It's nothing to worry about.
几乎每个人第一次下来都会有幽闭恐惧症的感觉。
Almost everybody gets a touch of claustrophobia first time down.
这不是幽闭恐惧症，上尉。
It's not claustrophobia, captain.
而是意识到，我们的使命终于开始了。
It's the realization that, at last, our mission has begun.
如果6个月前有人告诉我，今天我会在一艘开往北极水域的潜艇上，寻找一个秘密的原子基地……-我简直不敢相信。-我明白你的意思。
If anyone had told me six months ago that today I would be on a submarine headed for arctic waters in search of a secret atomic base... - I just can't believe it. - Yeah, I know what you mean.
嗯,嗯…你的助理呢，教授?
Well, uh... What about your assistant, professor?
是什么让一个长得那样的女孩迷上了科学?
What makes a girl who looks like that get mixed up in science?
她来自一个科学家家庭。
She comes from a family of scientists.
她是个神童。
She was a child prodigy.
14岁时，她进入了大学。
At 14, she entered college.
18岁时，她在哥廷根大学学习。
At 18, she studied at gottingen.
她真的很聪明。
She is really very brilliant.
身材神童的费舍，对吧?
A child prodigy with a body by Fisher, huh?
这是整个潜艇服务中最伟大的小艇。
And this is the greatest pigboat in the whole submarine service.
美国海军弓鳍鱼。
The USS bowfin.
这是我们一起服役的一次…我，队长，炮手，挖泥船和船长。
It's one we served on together... Me, the chief, gunner, dugboat and the skipper.
美丽的,不是吗?
Beautiful, ain't she?
哦,是的。非常漂亮。
Oh, yes. Very beautiful.
你知道还有一件很漂亮的事吗?
You know something else that's very beautiful?
我这辈子都想找到一个叫丹尼斯的女孩。
All my life I've been wanting to find a girl called Denise.
斯基，我相信你会找到她的。
Oh, ski, I'm sure you will find her.
我找到她了，没错。
Oh, I found her, all right.
你看，我很快就记住了你的名字。
You see, I lost no time at all in learning your first name.
是的。丹尼斯。它一直是我最喜欢的名字。
Yep. Denise. It's always been my favorite name.
我…我从没见过丹尼斯，但我知道我会的。
I... I never met a Denise, but I always knew I would.
你看，从我看到你的那一刻起，我就说"拉法耶，我来了"
You see, from the moment I saw you, I said, “Lafayette, I'm here.”
这是正确的。我就知道我会遇到一个叫丹尼斯的女孩。
That's right. I always knew I'd meet a girl called Denise.
D-e-n-i……别让他骗你，亲爱的。
D-e-n-i... Don't let him kid you, honey.
我刚看到他把你的名字写在胳膊上。
I just seen him put your name on his arm.
——看。-好吧，小家伙。你自找的!
- Look. - All right, bub. You asked for it!
不!
No!
过来，你这个大酒鬼!
Come here, you big drunkard!
这就是我所说的约拿。他们在对那位夫人发牢骚。
That's what I mean by Jonahs. They were beefing over the dame.
不是她的错。他僵硬的。
Wasn't her fault. He's stiff.
——她好吗?-是的。
- She okay? - Yeah.
只是受了点小伤。
Just roughed up a little.
好好照顾他，holter。
Take care of him, holter.
来，我来帮你，教授。
Oh, here, let me help you, professor.
——谢谢。——让我们看看。
- Thank you. - Let's see.
我真的很抱歉，教授。
I'm really very sorry about this, professor.
那个醉汉是临时替补的。
That drunk was a last-minute replacement.
-他清醒的时候很好。——我很抱歉。
- He's all right when he's sober. - I'm sorry.
这是我最后…我想发生。
This is the last thing I... I wanted to happen.
它迟早要爆发的。让我们再看一遍。
It had to break out sooner or later. Let's have another look here.
唷!幸运的是你的牙还在。
Whew! It's lucky you still got your teeth.
别紧张，医生。没人会咬你的。
Don't get nervous, doc. Nobody's gonna bite you.
你不认为如果必要的话，药剂师应该给我治疗吗?
Don't you think that the pharmacist should treat me, if it's necessary?
他那两个家伙忙得不可开交。
He's got his hands full with those two lugs.
再说，他能做的事我都能做。
Besides, there's nothing he can do that I can't, you know.
哦,我的。他把你弄得油腻腻的。
Oh, my. He got you so greasy.
好吧。
Okay.
你知道什么是圆木吗?
You know what a log is?
——是的。-是吗?
- Yes. - You do, huh?
我应该把发生的每件事都详细地记录下来。
Well, I'm supposed to keep a detailed report of everything that happens.
-是给藤森先生的。——嗯。
- It's for Mr. Fujimori. - Mm-hmm.
它是怎么开始的呢?
How'd it start?
我在研究一个新公式时，斯基问我能不能给我看看他的胸部。
I was working on a new formula when ski asked if he could show me his chest.
-给你看他的胸部?——是的。
- Show you his chest? - Yes.
然后呢?
And then what?
然后他脱下了衬衫。
Then he removed his shirt.
没有在开玩笑吧?
No kidding?
-他想让我看看他的纹身。-哦,不。
- He wanted me to see his tattoo. - Oh, no.
-很漂亮的纹身。-我打赌是的。
- It was a beautiful tattoo. - I'll bet it was.
——美丽。——嗯。
- Beautiful. - Mm-hmm.
-但醉酒的那个擦掉了。——自然。
- But the intoxicated one rubbed it off. - Naturally.
告诉我，他在挑逗你吗?
Tell me, uh, he make a pass at you?
——通过?-他想吻你吗?
- A pass? - Did he try to kiss you?
是的,他做到了。
Yes, he did.
他,是吧?你把他打昏了吗?
He did, huh? Did you coldcock him?
——什么?-你打他了吗?
- What? - Did you hit him?
等一下。等一下。
Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
电话。电话。现在，用英语说。
Hold the phone. Hold the phone. Now, say that in English.
-我扇了他一巴掌。-是吗?
- I slapped him. - You did, huh?
告诉我，他亲了你之后你打了他?
Uh, tell me, uh, you hit him after he kissed you?
——是的。-之前没有吧?
- Yes. - Not before, huh?
我不明白。
I do not understand.
你看，教授，我只是想确认我的报告是真实的。
Well, you see, professor, I just want to make sure my report is factual.
-我不能放…-琼斯上尉。
- I couldn't put... - Captain Jones.
这份报告是给藤森先生的还是给你的?
Is this report for Mr. Fujimori or for you?
——嗯…——嗯。
- Uh... - Mmm.
说真的，一个神童应该能弄明白。
Now, really, a child prodigy oughta be able to figure that one out.
你不觉得吗?
Don't you think?
——是的。——是的。
- Yes. - Yes.
再见,教授。
Au revoir, professor.
现在听我说。
Now listen to me.
我不想再跟你吵架了，明白吗?
I don't want any more beefs, you understand?
如果我听说有人对那个女孩动手动脚，我就亲自从一号鱼雷发射管把他射出来。
If I hear of anybody making a play for that girl, I'll personally shoot him out through torpedo tube number one.
队长，我们要去哪还是个秘密吗?
Captain, is it still a secret where we're goin'?
我们在追踪一艘货船去北太平洋的一个小岛。
We're tailin' a freighter to an island in the north pacific.
她会下沉?
Gonna sink her?
我们要溜进这个岛，看一看，然后溜出去。
We're gonna sneak into this island, take a look and sneak out.
这是一次科学考察。
This is a scientific expedition.
-但是，船长，我们在找什么?-四叶草。
- But, skipper, what are we lookin' for? - Four-leaf clovers.
如果岛上的人不喜欢我们怎么办?
Well, what if the guys on the island don't like us?
听着，我知道你们都渴望有行动，但只有在我们必须自卫的情况下，你们才会有行动，所以放松点。
Look, I know you're all itchin' for a little action, but you'll only get it if we have to defend ourselves, so relax.
琼斯Capitalne ?
Capitalne Jones?
Le capitalne琼斯。
Le capitalne Jones.
——嗯。——晚安。
- Mm-hmm. - Bonne nuit.
晚安。
Bonne nuit.
哦,早上好!
Oh, good morning!
-水够热吗，教授?-太好了，谢谢。
- Was the water hot enough, professor? - Just wonderful, thank you.
-你想"油烟" une c/garette?——Wh ?
- Voulez-vous ”fume” une c/garette? - Wh at?
-我在说法语。——哦。
- I'm speaking French. - Oh.
你想"油烟" une c/garette?
Voulez-vous ”fume” une c/garette?
你是说"我/oulez-vous fumer une c/garette "吗
Oh, you mean ”I/oulez-vous fumer une c/garette?”
-我就是这么说的——没有。是有益的。
- That's what I said. - No. Fumer.
——Foo-may。-不不不。
- Foo-may. - No, no, no.
你的嘴唇要像这样。
You have to form your lips like this.
是有益的。
Fumer.
我想我该走了。
I think I better go now.
谢谢你！
Thank you.
总有一天我会知道她眼睛是什么颜色的。
You know, someday I'm gonna find out what color her eyes are.
早上好，琼斯上尉。你找我?
Good morning, captain Jones. You wanted to see me?
你为什么让我在飞机上睡着了?
Why did you let me sleep through that plane contact?
我以为你需要休息。你当班将近20个小时。
I thought you needed the rest. You were on duty for almost 20 hours.
你就没想过这条信息有多重要吗?
Didn't you stop to think how important that message might be?
当然可以。
Of course.
所以我确定不是自己解码的。
So I made sure that it was not by decoding it myself.
如你所见，报告只说江青号的速度和航线没有改变。
As you see, it reports only that the kiang ching has made no change in speed or course.
我知道那不重要。
I knew that was of no importance.
教授，你有没有想过我可能会把这门课…你耽误了我们大约两个小时!
Professor, did it ever occur to you that I might be steering a course to be... You've lost us approximately two hours!
我很抱歉，队长。
I'm very sorry, captain.
-我想我学到了一些东西。-我希望如此。
- And I think I have learned something. - I hope so.
如果你想偷听谈话，就用对讲机。这是更容易。
If you want to listen in on conversations, use the intercom. It's easier.
我不希望听到这段对话。
That conversation I would prefer not to have heard.
-但我在等着见你。-好吧，你看我。我很忙。
- But I was waiting to see you. - Okay, you see me. I'm busy.
我和蒙泰尔教授共事多年了，但我从来没有听过有人像您这样对他这个领域里最伟大的科学家说话。
Many years have I been with professor montel, but never before have I heard anyone speak like you to the greatest scientist in his field.
蒙泰尔教授的领域不是指挥一艘古怪的潜艇。我的是。
Professor montel's field isn't commanding a screwball submarine. Mine is.
如果有必要这么无礼的话，我希望这次旅行时间很短。
If such rudeness is necessary, I hope this will be a very short cruise.
你找我有什么事?
What'd you want to see me about?
——Joto。——是的,先生?
- Joto. - Yes, sir?
将来，当一条消息传到这艘船上时，不管谁说这是不必要的，我都会收到，你明白吗?
In the future, when a message comes in to this boat, I get it, no matter who says it's unnecessary, you understand?
是的,先生。
Yes, sir.
Oh-oh-oh-oh-oh !
Oh-oh-oh-oh-oh!
不，不，不。
No, no, no, no.
这一次，他是对的。
This time, he was right.
我们可以从桥上走吗?
May we come on the bridge?
确定。帮助你自己。
Sure. Help yourself.
联络飞机正按计划接近!
Contact plane approaching on schedule!
不够好。
Good enough.
好吧,查理。
Okay, Charlie.
在这里!
There it is!
这个是给你的，医生。
Well, this one's for you, doc.
"情报报告江庆携带非传统61-j太空舱"
“Intelligence reports kiang ching carrying unconventional-type 61-j capsule.”
藤森签署。”“61-j太空舱是什么?”
Signed, “fujimori.” what's a 61-j capsule?
引爆原子弹的炸药
The charge to explode an a-bomb.
嗨,队长。雷达显示有物体接近，方位355度。
Hey, skipper. Radar shows surface object approaching, bearing 355 degrees.
——速度?-还不知道，但他在快速接近。
- Speed? - Can't tell yet, but he's closing fast.
——范围。- 3800码。
- Range. - 3,800 yards.
也许那艘货船看到了我们的信号，来追我们了。
Maybe the freighter has seen our signal and comes after us.
钻井平台为红色。
Rig for red.
一艘潜艇在追我们。
A sub's after us.
子吗?我以为这是科学考察。
A sub? I thought this was a scientific expedition.
是的，我们要谨慎行事。
It is, and we're gonna play it safe.
除非万不得已，否则流鼻血也没用。
No use getting a bloody nose unless we have to.
她在水下听我们说话。
She's submerged and listening for us.
-所以她才不再联系我-什么意思?
- That's why she stopped pinging. - What does this mean?
意思是她在保存鱼雷，等我们浮出水面。
It means she's saving her torpedoes, waiting till we surface.
再过一天，博士，我们就能把鱼雷发射管彻底检修完。
Just one more day, doc, and we'd have finished overhauling those torpedo tubes.
你能看到她的瞄准镜吗?
Can you see her scope?
我们也可以装死。
Well, we can play possum too.
-氢怎么样了?-增加到3%。
- How's the hydrogen? - Built up to three percent.
我们不能冒险在这里浮出水面。我们得跑了。
Well, we can't chance surfacing here. We've got to make a run for it.
教授，我觉得你们俩最好都待在自己的房间里。
Professor, I think you'd both better stay in your quarters.
范围。
Down scope.
他们还在船尾，船长。
They're still on our stern, skipper.
-氢气怎么样?-按我们的百分比计算，还在增加。
- How's that hydrogen gas? - F our percent and still building.
带她了!
Take her up!
好吧,查理。
Okay, Charlie.
你最好离桥远点，教授。
You better keep off the bridge, professor.
我不上去。
I'm not going up.
如果船长发现你在控制室，他会大发雷霆的。
The skipper'd blow his top if he even found you here in the control room.
-请坐，教授。抓住一些空气。——谢谢。
- Sit down, professor. Grab some air. - Thank you.
你认出潜水艇了吗?
Have you identified the submarine?
不。我们还没见过她呢。
No. We haven't even seen her yet.
他们在上面试图发现她。
They're topside trying to spot her now.
还没找到她，船长。
No sign of her yet, skipper.
声纳显示她就在附近。通知炮手。
Sonar tells us she's not far. Alert the gun crew.
——什么?——我知道。我们不是在找麻烦。
- What? - I know. We're not lookin' for trouble.
但不保护自己才是傻瓜。
But we'd be fools not to protect ourselves.
准备战斗!
Alert for battle stations!
炮手准备上甲板炮。
Gun crew stand by to man the deck gun.
那些鱼雷呢?
What about these torpedoes?
你知道那些管子还没检查过。忘记了鱼雷!
You know those tubes haven't been checked. Forget the torpedoes!
-她现在在哪里，joto?-范围,1500。
- Where is she now, joto? - Range, 1,500.
她要么搬出去，要么就会浮出水面。
Either she's moving out, or she's gonna surface.
她来了，船长!
There she is, skipper!
他们在甲板上。
They're coming out on deck.
问他们我们在哪，查理。
Ask them where we are, Charlie.
-为什么不现在就上5英寸的?——不!
- Why not man the five-incher now? - No!
一旦他们发现枪旁有船员，就会向我们发射鱼雷。
The minute they spot a crew near that gun, they'll throw torpedoes at us.
他们在说什么?
What are they saying?
他们想知道我们是谁，我们在这里干什么。
They want to know who we are and what we're doing here.
告诉他们我们是去北极的私人科学探险队。
Tell 'em we're a private scientific expedition headed for the arctic.
他们坚持要登船。
They insist on boarding us.
嗯,保持总得”。告诉他们我们不明白。
Well, keep stallin'. Tell 'em we don't understand.
请他们重复留言。
Ask them to repeat the message.
在船头放一个。让他们重复一遍，查理。
Put one over our bow. Keep asking them to repeat, Charlie.
把我们的鼻子转向她。带领001人。
Turn our nose into her. Steer 001.
准备好拿起枪。
And get ready to man that gun.
不要靠近救生索!
Keep clear of the lifeline!
右满舵。
Right full rudder.
鱼雷!
Torpedo!
清除甲板!清除甲板!
Clear the deck! Clear the deck!
潜水!
Dive!
关闭舱口!
Close the hatch!
我的手!我的手!
My hand! My hand!
我的手!
My hand!
-给我一把刀!——不!不!不!
- Give me a knife! - No! No! No!
在这里。
Here.
-他怎么样了?他是如何?-是他的拇指。
- How is he? How is he? - It's his thumb.
好吧。把他们都抓下来。
All right. Get 'em all below.
嘿,你们!快上来!帮我一把，快!
Hey, you guys! Come on up here! Give me a hand, quick!
我们装运的水太多了。拖不住她了。
We ship too much water. Can't hold her up.
把角度移开，让它沉到水底。
Get the angle off and let her settle to the bottom.
所有回满。
All back full.
敌人的鱼雷发射。
Enemy torpedo fired.
二号鱼从篮子里出来。
Number two fish out of their basket.
固定所有运转的机器。保持沉默。
Secure all running machinery. Remain silent.
舱底泵马达失灵，船长。
Bilge pump motor's fioodeo', skipper.
排成一排。把水倒进机舱的舱底。
Form a bucket line. Dump the water in the engine room bilges.
那个浴缸是为我们准备的，船长。她已经很接近了。
That tub's laying for us, skipper. She's coming real close.
我失去了她。
I lost her.
她现在什么都没说。没有声音。
Nothing out of her now. No sound.
你觉得呢，船长?
What do you think, skipper?
我觉得她跟我们耍的把戏一样。
I think she's pulling the same trick we are.
现在注意那海水。我们不希望船上有氯气。
Now watch that salt water. We don't want any chlorine gas in the boat.
持有它。
Hold it.
队长，这高温快把我们累死了。
Captain, this hot heat is killing us.
我们得把电扇打开。
We got to turn on the fans.
如果他们听到了我们的粉丝的声音，你就不用担心热死了，孩子。
If they heard our fans, you wouldn't have to worry about the heat killing you, boy.
好吧，我马上给你补充情况。
All right, I'll fill in the picture for you quick.
我们有鱼雷，但发射管无法发射。
We got torpedoes, but our tubes aren't in condition to fire 'em.
红色潜艇和我们一样停在海底，等着声纳发现我们。
And the red sub's parked on the bottom like we are, waitin' to pick us up on sonar.
一旦她这么做了，她会朝我们扔更多的鱼。
Once she does, she'll throw more fish at us.
所以问题是谁在没有空气的情况下能坚持得更久……是红色的还是我们。
So it's a question of who can hold out longer without air... the reds or us.
如果我们先突破，很有可能是最后一次突破。
If we break first, chances are it'll be our last break.
我们还装载了氢。
And we're loaded with hydrogen.
我们容易爆炸。
We're liable to explode.
但有一件事对我们有利。
But we got one thing in our favor.
我们可以通过闭上嘴来节省氧气。
We can save oxygen by shutting up.
这是所有。
That's all.
的,是吧?
Nothin', huh?
一文不值。
Nothin'.
我们得节省果汁。
We gotta save juice.
转移到红色。
Shift to red.
把耳朵竖起来，斯基。
Keep your ears open, ski.
很抱歉，队长，我太蠢了。
I am sorry, captain, for being so stupid.
没关系。别白费口舌了。
That's all right. Save your breath.
你必须用那把刀。
You had to use the knife.
如果你不关上舱门，我们都死了。
If you didn't close the hatch, we would all be dead.
你击败。
You're beat.
你最好回你的床上去，放松点。来吧。
You better get back to your bunk and take it easy. Come on.
-我想告诉你怎么…——嘘。
- I want to tell you how... - Shh.
不要说话。
Don't talk.
队长。
Skipper.
他的情况很糟糕。
He's in a bad way.
我以为注射麻醉药能起作用，但他休克了，还失血过多。
I thought that hypo was gonna do the trick, but he's sufferin' from shock and loss of blood.
如果他不马上呼吸点新鲜空气，你就只有一个教授了。
If he don't get some air right away, you're gonna have only one professor for cargo.
那张床上有5万美金。
There's 50 grand in that bunk.
五万块值一点空气。
Fifty grand is worth a little air.
乔托，把白灯打开。
Joto, turn on the white lights.
伙计们，我要试一试。
Boys, I'm gonna try a long shot.
如果前几颗鱼雷打偏了，我们还有机会。
If her first couple of torpedoes miss us, we got a chance.
我宁愿在没有空气的情况下昏倒，也不愿被鱼雷击中。
I'd rather pass out without air than have a torpedo come plowing through us.
当我们启动水泵时，很容易产生火花。
Now when we start the pump, we're liable to get a spark.
可能会燃烧掉氢，也可能不会。
Maybe it'll burn off the hydrogen, maybe it won't.
如果不行，我们就会迅速爆炸，你永远感觉不到。
If it doesn't, we'll blow up so fast you'll never feel it.
祝我们大家好运。
Good luck to all of us.
-你都准备好了吗?——是的,先生。
- You got everything straight? - Yes, sir.
现在我们来看看我们的生活是否正确。
Now here's where we find out if we've lived right.
没有爆炸的可能。把消息传下去。
No more chance of explosion. Pass the word along.
慢慢地转弯。
And build up the turns slowly.
-别出声。——是的,先生。
- Hold down the noise. - Yes, sir.
-领先三分之一。——是的,先生。
- All ahead one-third. - Yes, sir.
把她抬到175英尺，纽曼先生。
Take her up and level her to 175 feet, Mr. Neuman.
是的,先生。
Yes, sir.
她加速了，船长。
She's speeded up, skipper.
轴承240度。
Bearing 240 degrees.
右满舵!所有之前fiank !
Right full rudder! All ahead fiank!
-准备撞击!-准备撞击!
- Stand by to ram! - Stand by to ram!
距离200，方位010度。
Range 200, bearing 010 degrees.
离开满舵!把她降到190英尺。
Left full rudder! Take her down to 190 feet.
- - - - - - 190英尺。-准备撞击!
- 190 feet. - Stand by to ram!
所有,紧急!把所有主镇流器都炸毁!
All back, emergency! Blow all main ballasts!
船长!
Captain!
你就在那里。你确定你没事吗，医生?
There you are. Are you sure you're all right, doc?
-好的，谢谢。——好的。
- Yes, thank you. - All right.
现在深吸一口新鲜空气。
Now take a good deep breath of fresh air.
感觉还好吧，挖泥船?
Feel all right, dugboat?
是的。对于一次安静的科学考察，我感觉好极了。
Yeah. For a quiet scientific expedition, I couldn't feel better.
你看起来糟透了。让我看看你的舌头。
You look awful. Let me see your tongue.
请进，请进。
J“ in, please j“
让我有足够的地面，这样我就可以绕着j跳。
j“ let me have plenty ground so that I can hopping round j“
请不要把我关起来
j“ not fencing me in, please j“
让我有个小房子
j“ let me have little house j“
J“竹席制J”
j“ made of bamboo mat j“
j "哦，请不要把我在的地方围起来"
j“ oh, please not putting fence around where I am at j“
j“我需要很大的空间，这样我才能摇摆猫j”
j“ I'm needing lots of room so I can swinging cat j“
不要把我困在J里
j“ not fencing me in j“
让我有棵树，这样小鸟就会筑巢
J“ let me have a tree so the birdies will make nest j“
J "和/可以吃燕窝汤J "
j“ and / can having bird nest soup j“
一切都很酷，伙计。
it all real cool, man.
让我在那边自由自在
J“ just set me free way out yonder j“
我会成为一个独立的傻瓜
j“ and ill be an independent nincompoop j“
结束了，杰克逊。
this are the end, Jackson.
J " /想在草上露着露珠的早晨醒来。
J“ / want to wake in the morning when the grass is dewy j“
看着我的小女人做饭，苏，y, J
j“ watch my little woman while she cook chop sue y j“
J "有栅栏围着我是一件很有趣的事。"
j“ having fence around me is a lot of hooe y j“
不要把我困在J里
j“ not fencing me in j“
我正在学习法语。就像李成学的那首美国歌。
I'm learning French. You know, like chin Lee learned that American song.
你在浪费时间，小子。
You're wasting your time, junior.
-你好。
-Hello.
如果那音乐打扰到你，我可以把它关掉。
Say, uh, if that music disturbs you, I could have it turned off.
哦,不。我…我喜欢音乐。
Oh, no. I... I love music.
——哦。了吗?——嗯。
- Oh. That? - Mm-hmm.
你的手怎么样，教授?
Well, how's the hand, professor?
很好，船长，你看。
Wonderful, captain, as you see.
好。很高兴听你这么说。
Good. Glad to hear it.
-你好吗，教授?-我很好，谢谢。
- And how are you, professor? - I'm fine, thank you.
——膨胀。你知道，当我…-琼斯船长，请到上面来。对不起，是属于土地所有权的。
- Swell. You know, uh, when I... - Captain jonesl come topside, please. Fre/ghter in s/ght of land excuse me.
好的机会。
Bonne chance.
我不明白你的意思。
I don't understand.
我们的情报报告不可能错得这么离谱。
Our intelligence report cannot be this wrong.
我们得到的只是正常的计数。
All we are getting is a normal count.
-你应该高兴。——别误会。
- You ought to be happy. - Don't misunderstand.
没有什么比知道我们的怀疑毫无根据更让我高兴的了。
Nothing would please me more than to know that our suspicions are unfounded.
那我们走吧。
Then let's move out.
这里除了破旧的加里森和一些破旧的储油罐什么都没有。
There's nothin' here but this two-bit Garrison and some beat-up storage tanks.
很遗憾我不能和他们说话。
It's a great pity I cannot talk to them.
我们是天壤之别。但毕竟，他们也是人。
We are worlds apart. But, after all, they are human.
——走吧。——但纽曼。
- Let's go. - But neuman.
算了吧。一枪爆头。
Forget it. Shot right through the head.
我们走吧。
Let's get out of here.
斯基，试着把灯弄灭!
Ski, try to knock out that light!
好了，加油!我们快离开这里!
All right, come on! Let's get outta here!
你黄色的狗!
You yellow dogs!
来吧,滑雪。帮我一下。让我们把他弄上船。
Come on, ski. Give me a hand. Let's get him in the boat.
你想和其中一个人类说话。我给你带了一个。
You wanted to talk to one of these humans. I got one for you.
把你们的外套弄湿。
Wet down your coats.
他们肯定在整个地区找我们，但目前还没找到，对吧?
Well, they must be combing the whole area for us, but so far, nothin', huh?
连一只海鸥都没有。
Not even a seagull.
嘿，挖泥船，你确定我擦在胸口的果冻不会吃掉我的纹身吗?
Hey, dugboat, you sure this jelly I'm rubbin' on my chest won't eat off my tattoo?
你在担心什么?你可以再买一个。
What are you worried about? You can always get another.
你疯了吗?这就是我的"阻力"
Are you nuts? That's my “piece de resistance.”
-你的什么?——这是法语。
- Your piece de what? - That's French.
我一直在练习“尼斯巴人?”
I been practicing, “Nessie-pas?”
你需要多练习。
You need more practice.
琼斯上尉。l/lontel教授要你去医务室。
Captain Jones. Professor ll/lontel wants to see you in sick bay.
-还要咖啡吗?——没有。不用了，谢谢你，李成。谢谢你！
- Want more coffee? - No. No, thank you, chin Lee. Thank you.
这是美妙的。
This is wonderful.
-你想见我，教授?——是的。
- You want to see me, professor? - Yes.
丹尼斯刚刚翻译了他的命令。
Denise has just translated his orders.
他的名字叫何新。他是一名飞行员，要去凯夫洛克岛执行特殊任务。
His name is ho sin. He's a pilot en route to kevlock island for special duty.
那又怎样?
So what?
凯夫洛克一定是泰勒拍摄的那个岛船长。
Kevlock must be the island captain Taylor photographed.
你怎么知道的?
Well, how do you figure that?
一个空军飞行员很难被分配到一个没有飞机跑道的岛上执行任务。
An air force pilot would hardly be assigned to duty on an island without an airstrip.
如你所知，kevlock是这条链中唯一一个有名字的岛。
And as you know, kevlock is the only island indicated by name in this entire chain.
它似乎在我们现在位置的正北方。
It appears to be due north of our present position.
那你觉得我们该怎么做?
And what do you suggest we do about it?
在我看来，我们的路线是显而易见的。
It seems to me our course is obvious.
-在我看来不是，医生。-什么意思?
- Not in my book, doc. - What do you mean?
我是说你曾经说过每个人都有自己活着的理由和死的代价。
I mean you said once that each man's got his own reason for living and his own price for dying.
我活着的理由就是五万美元。
Well, my reason for living is 50 grand.
我不会再冒险了。
I'm not sticking my neck out again.
-一条脖子这么重要吗，队长?-当它是我的时候就是。
- Is one neck that important, captain? - It is when it's mine.
你是什么样的人?
What kind of man are you?
持有它。持有它。
Hold it. Hold it.
我们不要和那些含糊其辞的人联合起来。
Let's not gang up with a lot of double-talk.
我是一个商人。
I'm a businessman.
也许对你们这种摇摆不定的人来说，我是个雇佣兵。好吧。
Maybe to a couple of fiag-wavers like you, I'm a mercenary. All right.
但我履行了我的义务。
But I lived up to my part of the contract.
我们说好的是跟踪货船到岛上，把你弄上岸，然后送你回东京。
The deal was to tail the freighter to the island, put you ashore and get you back to Tokyo.
没人说过还有第二座岛。
Nobody said anything about a second island.
所以在我看来，任务完成了。我们要回家了。
So as far as I'm concerned, mission completed. We're going home.
反对吗?
Any objections?
是的。
Yes.
我讨厌使用权力，但如果有必要，我会的。
I hate to use authority, but if I have to, I will.
我不希望事情发展到这一步。
I didn't want it to come to this.
但既然你提到了合同，仔细研究一下，船长。
But as long as you have mentioned the contract, study it closely, captain.
你会发现有一段话是这样说的:我，只有我，将决定任务何时完成。
You will find a paragraph stating that I, and I alone, shall determine when the mission is finished.
在我看来，船长，任务会在我被带到凯夫洛克，有机会检查岛屿并返回东京后结束。
And in my book, captain, the mission will be finished after I am taken to kevlock, given the chance to examine the island and returned to Tokyo.
——Joto。——是的,先生。
- Joto. - Yes, sir.
-朝正北走。-你说不?
- Head due north. - Did you say non'h?
你没听错。设定新的航向去凯夫洛克岛。
You heard me. Set a new course for kevlock island.
-在你的病历上。——是的,先生。
- It's on your chart. - Yes, sir.
好了，医生，我们走。
Okay, doc, let's go.
有什么事吗?
What's the matter?
我的膝盖。
My knee.
-我以为你今天早上说可以的。——这是。
- I thought you said it was okay this morning. - It was.
-我过一会儿就好。-不可能。你只会碍事。
- I'll manage in a few moments. - Not a chance. You'd just be in the way.
-明天会改善的。我很确定。——对不起,医生。
- It will improve by tomorrow. I'm sure of it. - Sorry, doc.
我们不会在这片水域待太久的。这是一个火药桶。
We're not hanging around these waters that long. This is a powder keg.
等待。等一下。等一下。这是怎么呢你在说什么?
Wait. Wait a minute. Wait a minute. What's going on? What are you talking about?
琼斯上尉，我的助手会陪你。
Captain Jones, my assistant will accompany you.
什么?
What?
她受过足够的训练来计算数字，确定力量和识别岛上的要素。
She has sufficient training to compute figures, determine strength and identify elements if there are any on this island.
你的意思是你会……你会让她走?
You mean you'd... you'd let her go?
除了我，杰勒德教授是探险队中唯一有能力完成这项任务的人。
With the exception of me, professor Gerard is the only member of this expedition capable of performing this task.
-你们俩都疯了。-你带她上岸，按照我的指示去做。
- Oh, you're both crazy. - You will take her ashore and follow her instructions as you would have followed mine.
她不能去，就这么定了。
She is not going, and that's final.
你还是不能下命令，对吧，琼斯上尉?
You still cannot take an order, can you, captain Jones?
裂缝后面是什么?
And what's behind that crack?
跟你想的完全一样。
Exactly what you think is behind it.
斯基，你留在这里。睁大眼睛。
Ski, you stay here. Keep your eyes open.
关于她的什么?我可以帮她拿设备。
What about her? I could carry her equipment.
她能处理好自己的设备。
She can take care of her own equipment.
嘘!
Psst!
看看下面。
Take a look down there.
看起来像一堆门。
Looks like a bunch of doors.
恐怕我们已经找到我们要找的东西了。
I'm afraid we have found what we are looking for.
这样的盖革反反应只能说明一件事。
A geiger counter reaction like this can mean only one thing.
这些数字……
These figures...
他们在说什么?
What are they saying?
他们在找lumfong，一个失踪的士兵。
They are looking for lumfong, a missing soldier.
我们得等他们搬走。来吧。
We gotta stay put till they move out. Come on.
你说我还是不能接受订单是什么意思?
What did you mean when you said I still can't take an order?
你的记录,船长。
Your record, captain.
在战争中，你是个很好的军官，除了一件事。
In the war you were a very good officer, except for one thing.
继续。我着迷。
Go on. I'm fascinated.
你可以下命令，但你不能接受。
You could give orders, but you couldn't take them.
现在看来,我…我知道你在说什么。
Now look, I... I know what you're talking about.
但如果你想知道一个人的动力是什么，你就不能只看记录。
But if you want to know what makes a guy tick, you've got to look beyond the record.
那些菲律宾游击队被隔绝和包围了。
Those philippine guerrillas were cut off and surrounded.
他们必须有弹药和补给。
They had to have ammunition and supplies.
我不能坐在我的罐子上让他们死。
I couldn't just sit there on my can and let 'em die.
我知道水已经被挖空了，但我想我可以毫发无损地进出。
I knew the waters were mined, but I figured I could get in, get out without a scratch.
所以我写了自己的命令。
So I wrote my own orders.
我失去了潜艇和26个人。
I lost my sub and 26 men.
如果!必须的，我还会再做一次。
And if! Had to, I'd do it again.
我很抱歉……非常抱歉。
I'm sorry... Very sorry.
我提这事都是不对的。
It was wrong of me even to mention it.
算了吧。一切都结束了。
Forget it. It's all over.
-你还好吧?——好。
- You all right? - Fine.
这一切结束后，如果我们回来了，你怎么了?
When this is over, if we get back, what gives with you?
——给了吗?-我是说，你打算怎么办?
- Gives? - I mean, what are you gonna do?
我想是回巴黎吧?
Go back to Paris, I suppose, huh?
-巴黎是我的家。-是的。
- Paris is my home. - Yeah.
你呢?
And you?
这一切结束后，你会怎样?
When this is over, what gives with you?
我不知道。
I don't know.
你去过巴黎吗?
Have you ever been in Paris?
不,从来没有。
No, never.
你会喜欢的。
You would love it.
美国人总是这样。
Americans always do.
我们不能待在这里。
Well, we can't stay here.
如果他们把我们拖到早上，我们可能就回不去了。
If they hold us up till morning, we might never get back.
我去看看有没有别的路出去。来吧。
I'm gonna see if there's another way out of here. Come on.
你呆在这里。我马上回来。
You stay here. I'll be right back.
在这里。
Here.
你不需要这个，但有时看到它是一种安慰。
You won't need this, but sometimes the sight of it's a comfort.
我马上就回来。
I'll be back in a minute.
Lumfong !
Lumfong!
丹尼斯!
Denise!
给我。来吧。我们走吧。
Give me that. Come on. Let's get out of here.
来吧。
Come on.
快点。来吧。
Hurry up. Come on.
来吧。
Come on.
我们走吧。
Let's go.
这证实了我们最担心的事情。
This confirms our worst fears.
原子反应是明确无误的。
The atomic reaction is unmistakable.
我不明白。
I don't get it.
我是说，我不明白为什么那个炸弹客会出现在跑道上。
I mean, I can't figure out why that bomber was on the runway.
一架b-29在红色的空军基地做什么?
What would a b-29 be doin' on a red air base?
这根本说不通。
It just doesn't make sense.
对了，你不是告诉我我们在另一个岛上抓到的那个红色军官是空军吗?
Say, didn't you tell me that that red officer we picked up on the other island was in the air force?
是的。一个主要的。
Yes. A major.
-你问过他吗?——不可能的。
- Were you ever able to question him? - Impossible.
-我试过了，但他一句话也不说。——哦。
- I tried, but he would not say a word. - Oh.
哦,谢谢。
Oh, thanks.
你和那个中国囚犯chin Lee谈过了吗?
Hey, did you talk to that Chinese prisoner, chin Lee?
他没有看见那个囚犯。
He has not seen the prisoner.
犯人没有见过他。
The prisoner has not seen him.
霍特，把便携麦克风挖出来放在鱼雷室里。
Holter, dig up that portable microphone and plant it in the torpedo room.
那就把犯人关在里面。别让他看到麦克风。
Then get the prisoner and lock him in there. Make sure he doesn't see the microphone.
——正确的。-拉他一把，斯基。
- Right. - Give him a hand, ski.
来吧。我们穿些干衣服吧。我们有工作要做。
Come on. Let's get into some dry clothes. We got work to do.
-你有计划?-我要搞清楚这到底是怎么回事。
- You have a plan? - I'm gonna find out what this is all about.
加油，chin Lee。我们有份工作给你。我们走吧。
Come on, chin Lee. We got a job for you. Let's go.
-你们都准备好了吗?——是的。
- You guys got everything set? - Yep.
好吧。
Okay.
你确定阿成·李完全明白他该说什么吗?
Now, you're sure chin Lee understands exactly what he's supposed to say, huh?
-他说什么?-他说他愿意为你做任何事。
- What'd he say? - He says he would do anything for you.
他想让你打他的脸让他看起来更真实。
He wants you to strike him in the face to make it look more real.
霍尔特。
Holter.
他想让你去做。
He wants you to do it.
他说你这样做不会痛。
He says it will not hurt if you do it.
你没事吧，孩子?你没事吧?
You all right, boy? You okay?
他的意思是什么?
What's he sayin'?
他说……犯人很聪明，一定是被愚弄了。
He says... The prisoner is very intelligent and must be fooled.
他想让你打他…困难。
He wants you to hit him... harder.
对不起,朋友。
I'm sorry, pal.
好了，把他弄出来。我们走吧。
All right, get him out. Let's go.
在这里。来吧。把他们。
Here. Come on. Take 'em.
这是难以置信的。
This is incredible.
这是怎么回事，船长?
What's it all about, skipper?
这是有史以来最离奇的情节。
This is the screwball plot of all time.
他们会在朝鲜或者满洲投下原子弹然后怪到我们头上。
They're gonna drop an atomic bomb on Korea or manchuria and blame it on us.
他们将在明天黎明乘坐改造过的轰炸机起飞。
They're taking off tomorrow at dawn in that made-over bomber.
他发现了他!
He found him out!
让我有足够的地面，这样我就可以绕着
J“ let me have plenty ground so that I can hop around j“
请不要把我关起来
j“ not fencing me in, please j“
让我有个小房子
j“ let me have little house j“
J“竹席制J”
j“ made of bamboo mat j“
j "哦，请不要把我在的地方围起来"
j“ oh, please not putting fence around where I am at j“
j“我需要很大的空间，这样我才能摇摆猫j”
j“ I'm needing lots of room so I can swinging cat j“
现在听我说。
Now listen to me.
我要一个人去岛上。
I'm shoving off for the island alone.
我就停在这里，在洞口附近。
I'll park myself right here, around the mouth of this cave.
你会潜到离跑道半英里的地方，就在这里，这样你就能看到我的信号了。
You'll submerge half a mile beyond the runway, right around here, so you'll be able to spot my signal.
大量的燃料会让轰炸机飞得很低。
Now a heavy load of fuel's gonna bring that bomber out low.
所以当我给你信号…两个短，两个长，两个短……那就意味着飞机要起飞了。
So when I give you the signal... Two short, two long, two short... That'll mean the plane's taking off.
这样你就有足够的时间浮出水面开火。
That'll give you just time enough to surface and fire.
我要每把枪都投入战斗。
I want every gun in action.
这意味着每一个人。
That means everybody.
那架飞机必须被击落。
That plane has to be knocked out of the sky.
你一撞到它，就冲到底部，待在那里，因为当炸弹击中它的时候，一切都会失控。
Now the minute you hit it, crash dive to the bottom and stay there, because everything's gonna break loose when that bomber hits.
北边尽头有个小海湾，就在这里。我就藏在那里。
There's a cove at the north end, right here. That's where I'll hide.
明晚十点整，我给你三个短眼罩。
Tomorrow night at 10:00 sharp, I'll give you three short blinkers.
接我。
Pick me up.
如果我没出现，你就离开，回家。
If I don't show up, shove off, head for home.
有什么问题吗?
Any questions?
我禁止这种疯狂的行为。
I forbid this insanity.
禁止你想做的一切，教授。那架飞机撑不过去了。
Forbid all you want to, professor. That plane is not gonna make it.
带回我们的怀疑得到证实的可怕报告已经够可怕的了。
It is dreadful enough to bring back the terrifying report that our suspicions are confirmed.
但我们不能承担起挑起战争的责任，不管我们感觉如何。
But we cannot take it upon ourselves to commit an act of war, no matter how we feel.
我们是平民!
We are civilians!
这次探险由我负责。
I am responsible for this expedition.
我命令你把这艘潜艇带回东京!
I order you to take this submarine back to Tokyo!
我不在乎你和你的探险。
I don't care about you and your expedition.
外面有一架敌方轰炸机伪装成美国轰炸机的样子。
There's an enemy bomber out there made up to look like an American bomber.
它会掉下史上最大的蛋，而我们要承担罪责。
It's gonna drop the biggest egg in history, and we're gonna take the rap for it.
我不喜欢那样。
I don't like that.
所以从现在开始，教授，这是我的远征。
So from now on, professor, this is my expedition.
队长!
Skipper!
船走了!
The boat's gone!
——什么?-船不见了。蒙特尔了它。
- What? - The boat's gone. Montel took it.
-那你为什么不阻止他?-我们没有机会。
- Well, why didn't you stop him? - We didn't get the chance.
他和她在甲板上。在我们知道发生了什么之前，他已经在船上走了。
He was on deck with her. Before we knew what happened, he was in the boat and gone.
-那个女孩在哪?-在桥上。
- Where's the girl? - On the bridge.
请。他不想让你阻止他。
Please. He doesn't want you to stop him.
你为什么不阻止他?你只要喊一声就行了。
Why didn't you stop him? All you had to do was yell.
他知道你的计划。他会执行的。这是他的命令。
He knows your plan. He'll carry it out. That's his orders.
这就是你们这些天才的问题所在……充满了伟大的想法。
That's the trouble with you geniuses... Full of big ideas.
现在你把一切都搞砸了。
Now you're fouling up the whole works.
-你知道那个岛上到处都是士兵。-他也知道
- You know that island's crawling with soldiers. - He knows that too.
那你为什么让这么好的一个老家伙抄近路去墓地?
Then why'd you let a nice old guy like that take a shortcut to the cemetery?
他不是普通的二流教授，你知道的。
He's no ordinary two-bit professor, you know.
他是蒙特尔，他的领域里的顶尖人物。
He's montel, top man in his field.
但他又老又无助……除了试管，他什么都不知道。
But he's old and helpless... doesn't know his way outside of a test tube.
你应该知道的。你和他合作得够近了。
You oughta know that. You work close enough with him.
-你是什么样的女人?——停止!
- What kind of a woman are you? - Stop!
-你没有感觉吗?——停止!
- Haven't you got any feelings? - Stop!
他是我的父亲。
He's my father.
什么?
What?
我的父亲。
My father.
哦，对不起，丹尼斯。
Oh, I'm sorry, Denise.
我很抱歉。原谅我。
I'm sorry. Forgive me.
他说那是他要去的地方……不是你的。
He said it was his place to go... Not yours.
我很抱歉。
I'm sorry.
她真的很有胆量。
She's sure got a lot of guts.
我唯一不明白的是为什么会有这么大的谜团?
Only thing I can't figure out is why the big mystery?
她为什么不告诉我们他是她老爸?
Why didn't she let us know he's her old man?
这就是有个名人父亲的代价。
Well, that's what you have to pay for having a famous father.
她一生都在一个位置上。
She's been on a spot all her life.
想自力更生，她做到了。
Wanted to make good on her own, and she did.
他很自豪，因为她做到了。
And he was proud because she did.
看到他了吗?
Any sign of him at all?
不,还没有。
No, not yet.
他就在这里。
There he is.
这是他的信号。
And there's his signal.
战斗表面!枪行动!范围!
Battle surface! Gun action! Down scope!
-你最好下去。——请。
- You'd better get below. - Please.
好吧。
Okay.
好吧,滑雪。我们走吧。
All right, ski. Let's go.
来吧,威利。乔托，上来。
Come on, Willie. Joto, get up here.
快点起来。快点起来。
Hurry it up. Hurry it up.
火!
Fire!
你对吧?
You all right?
——哦。-炸弹一定是在我们脚下爆炸了。
- Oh. - The bomb must have gone off under us.
让她回到航线上。
Bring her back on course.
带她到潜望镜深度。
Take her up to periscope depth.
潜望镜深度。
Periscope depth.
各舱报告损坏和伤亡情况。
All compartments, report damage and casualties.
轰炸机并没有坠入大海。
The bomber didn't crash in the ocean.
它袭击了小岛。
It hit the island.
往家走。
Head for home.
每个人都有自己活着的理由，琼斯先生，也都有自己的死的代价。
Each man has his own reason for living, Mr. Jones, and his own price for dying.